# MICHAEL ZARICK

### CUSTOMER SUCCESS LEAD

502-403-6120		michaelzarick.com	Fayetteville, AR	
--------------	--	-------------------	------------------	--

### PROFILE STATEMENT

People-focused and passionate **Customer Success Lead** with *over five years of experience* working with various start-ups to build a culture of learning, customer retention, and outreach to help drive brand awareness. Excellent communication and interpersonal skills while being committed to fostering a vibrant and inclusive community environment.

### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Community Engagement

**Technical Troubleshooting** 

**Project Management** 

Cross-functional Collaboration

**Customer Support** 

Crisis Management

Learning New Tools

### **Product Tools**

Slack

Hubspot

Airtable

Height

### SKILLS OVERVIEW

- ✓ Onboarding and implementation using all the tools at my disposal to get customers invested, on track, and get them over the line in a reasonable time
- ✓ **Influential and creative solutions** for the ideation and execution of products that boost the value proposition to executive stakeholders and investors
- ✓ **Design thinking approach that helps understand the user** and works with sales teams, designers, and engineers to bring solutions to customer issues
- ✓ Demonstrated ability to improve KPIs by updating product managers and other stakeholders on roadblocks to customer growth
- ✓ Proven track record in optimizing operational metrics through proactive communication of organizational performance and growth impediments
- ✓ Elevated knowledge of DEI that ensures target audiences feel that their voices are heard and acknowledged by figureheads of the business

### RECENT CUSTOMER SUCCESS IMPACTS

- Managed projects for high-profile clients, navigating their transition between e-commerce platforms with minimal disruption
- Grew the quantity of active accounts 70% within a year, employing strategic customer outreach and personalized onboarding
- Conceptualized an innovative customer onboarding process, facilitating the activation of numerous local merchant accounts
- Assisted engineering and sales in understanding the voice of the customer through storytelling and user data
- Evaluated product visions with cross-staff members to design roadmaps and adhere to tight deadlines
- Solved over 2000 customer issues by providing educational resources, personalized emails and hands on help in the past year
- Handled system-wide registration of Twilio A2P 10DLC avoiding loss of functionality across the platform for all customers

### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

# "Thank you so much for really listening and caring so much about the customer experience with your platform." - Customer feedback on support

# Customer Success Lead | Bottle.com

2021 - Present

- Strategized the new customer onboarding process, leading to the successful activation of 60+ accounts
- Championed the migration of 50+ customers from a 1.0 product to an upgraded 2.0 product, ensuring smooth onboarding and implementation in line with previously established best practices or customer preferences
- Handled customer issues efficiently, creating 50+ educational help articles and resolving over 2000 customer queries
- Delivered product feedback and detailed bug reports the product team, contributing to overall product enhancement
  Key Achievement: Overhauled all company onboarding and support practices leading to high customer retention

# Gaming Organization Manager | Team Opulence

2021-2022

- Assembled and managed three professional Valorant teams, fostering their development as efficient team members
- Guided over 20 players to becoming influential brand representatives, teaching them to develop professionally, manage their public social media persona, and cultivate a culture of hard work and trust
- Successfully created a Twitter social media following in just two months, fostering brand recognition and loyalty

Key Achievement: Achieved rapid social media growth demonstrating effective brand promotion strategies

### Customer Success Lead | Rebel Inc.

2020 - 2021

- · Executed onboarding and sales for customers nationwide, establishing online communities to foster business growth
- · Ensured top-notch quality of website and mobile apps by regular functionality, feature testing and quality assurance

Key Achievement: Set up over 30 diverse merchant accounts, through the creation of engaging online communities

# Counselor in Training Director | YMCA Camp Piomingo

2013 - 2017

- Empowered 30+ prospective counselors with effective leadership and communication skills.
- Planned and executed daily schedules and lessons focusing on self-improvement, fulfillment, and professionalism

**Key Achievement:** Developed a comprehensive training program for prospective counselors, equipping them with the skills to excel in their roles

### EDUCATION

#### **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

2019

Specialization: Computer Languages

Indiana University Bloomington, IN